TIFFANY GREVIOUS

(570) 234-4778 | tjgrevious@gmail.com | devchamploo.github.io | codepen.io/DevchamploO

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Languages: Ruby on Rails, Java, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5/CSS3; Frontend: Wordpress, JQuery, React, Redux; Backend: Node.js, Express, Spring Boot, MySQL, MongoDB; Other: GIT, Bash/Shell, D3, unit testing

PROJECTS

Crisis to Hope, https://github.com/DevchamploO/Crisis to Hope

 Web application that scans tweets for possible depression and suicide risk. Built with React, Bootstrap, Node/Express backend server, Twitter API, IBM Watson Tone Analyzer API, and peer reviewed research.

Filler.js, https://github.com/DevchamploO/filler.js

· Light weight JavaScript plugin that autofills filler text inside of HTML. Published to npm.

Fix Your City, https://github.com/DevchamploO/FixYourCity

· Hackathon submission. Report and rank local infrastructural damage to bring awareness and combat urban decay. Built with **React**, **Ruby on Rails**, and the **TomTom API**.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - Current

Web Developer, SEMnexus

- · Work collaboratively with clients and in-house team members to provide rapid and robust web development solutions.
- · Create and update custom solutions for Wordpress and Shopify.
- · Optimized websites for usability, search engine optimization and accessibility.
- \cdot Developed dynamic and interactive websites for Wordpress and Shopify.

2015 - 2018

Analyst, Appen Global

- · Partnered with web development teams to enhance functionality, user experience, online brand positioning and advertising.
- · Conducted research, evaluations, and provided feedback of various data sets.
- · Improved the quality of artificial intelligence for large Social Media companies and Google.

EDUCATION

2018

Software Engineering, 42 Sillicon Valley

2008 - 2012

Media Arts, New Jersey City University